# SPENCER HAYES-LAVERDIÈRE

Montreal, Canada · 438-407-5805

spencer.hayes@meiacademy.com· in/spencerhayeslaverdiere · https://spencer-hayes.me/

Passionate data scientist and machine learning engineer with experience solving real-world problems in computer-vision, natural language processing, and finance. Currently leading the data initiative at a retail tech startup focused on scan-and-go and autonomous checkouts.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **2021 - CURRENT**

## DATA SCIENTIST & MANAGER, <u>LEAV</u>

- Lead the development and deployment of a real-time recommendation system.
- Designed and integrated a robust data pipeline to store anonymized app usage data in a data lake.
- Developed and deployed a dashboard API capable of serving historical metrics to hundreds of stores simultaneously

#### MAY 2021 - SEP 2021

# DATA SCIENTIST – CONTRACT PART-TIME, ANAGRAPH

- Providing data analyses to clients with a specialization in geospatial data.
- Developing custom location intelligence tools
- Improving in-house data science practices and tooling.

#### 2020 - 2021

### MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, SQUAREFEET.AI

- Leading the development of pricing algorithms and models.
- Integrating explainable AI tools such as SHAP to give insights on models and track metrics like class bias on model performance.
- Training and deploying cloud models through AWS' SageMaker.

#### 2018 - 2020

# **INSTRUCTOR, UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA**

- Taught enrichment courses in Electrical & Computer Engineering
- Led in-school workshops teaching young kids engineering skills such as coding and 3D printing

# **SKILLS**

- Bilingual (English/French)
- Statistics/Machine Learning: Statistical Analysis, Linear/Logistic Regression, Clustering, Encoding/Decoding, CNNs, RNNs
- Data tools: Python, Java, C, FPGA, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, AWS, GCP, Git, DVC, Linux
- Explainable AI: SHAP, LIME

# **ARTICLES**

Finding Seasonal Trends in Time-Series Data with Python. Towards Data Science. Jun 7, 2021

# **EDUCATION**

2016 - 2020

# BASC COMPUTER ENGINEERING (CO-OP), UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA

Minor in Business Management & Entrepreneurship.

Capstone: Land-robot and aerial drone co-operative autonomous system.